University of Connecticut 2010.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Vice President & Chief Financial Officer Records
undated, 1999-2009.
2010.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
11.7 Linear feet
The Vice President and Chief Financial Officer is responsible for coordinating the development of financial plans, implementing the annual budget, financial reporting, accounting and debt management.
University of Connecticut. Vice President & Chief Financial Officer..
Box 2
Box 3
Box 4
Box 5
Box 1
Box 6
Box 7
Box 8
Box 9
History
The Vice President and Chief Financial Officer is responsible for coordinating the development of financial plans, implementing the annual budget, financial reporting, accounting and debt management.On par with Provost and Vice President and Chief Operating Officer, the VP&CFO reports to the President.
Finance and Administration separated into two departments in 1988 and reunited in 1991. The responsibilities were again separated in 2000 with the appointment of Lorraine Aronson. Records documenting the finances of the institution dated prior to 1999 can be found in the Records of the VP&COO.
Chief Clerk and Purchasing Agent, Treasurer, Comptroller
Raymond I. Longley, 1916-1943
Comptroller
Leonard C. Riccio, 1943-1958/9
Vice President for Finance and Administration
John M. Evans, 1960-1973
Richard J. DeHaan, 1973-1975
Harry J. Hartley 1975-1978
C. Edward Hanna (acting), 1978-1979
Arthur L. Gillis, 1979-1984
Harry J. Hartley, 1984-1988
Wilbur R. Jones, 1991-1998
Vice President for Finance
Thomas R. Popplewell, (interim), 1988-1989
Wilbur R. Jones, 1989-1991
Vice President and Chief Financial Officer
Lorraine Aronson, 2000-2008
Richard Gray, 2008-
Scope and Content
The collections contains documents, reports, studies and correspondence pertaining to the finances of the institution from 1999 to the present. Earlier materials can be found in the Records of the VP&COO, particularly in Series VIII.
Arrangement
The materials are listed as boxed and transferred by the creating office.
Series I: Records ( 1999-2009 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The records were transferred to the Archives in late 2009.
University of Connecticut.; Administrative Records.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Photographs.; Storrs (Conn.)
- Series I: Records, 1999-2009
  - UConn Health Center (Box 1)
    - Consortium/IME/GME
    - Pharmacy
    - Hebrew Home
    - Public Health, including Lab
    - Federal REvenue max.
    - OCHA
    - EVIS/IVS/TRICARE
    - Verterans' Services
    - Hospital Hardship Fund; Charity Care; Medicaid rate appeal
    - Personnel
      - Faculty salary
      - Faculty unionization
      - 1199 Tuition waiver
      - Residents
      - Sodexho
      - OJE
    - CHEFA
    - Malpractice management and counsel
    - Dental Medicine
    - Munson Road property
    - Farmington Surgery Center/MARB
    - Finance Corp.
  - (Box 2)
    - Correctional Managed Health Care
      - General files
      - Budget
      - OP & A agreement
      - Mental Health program
      - Audit
      - SOS/ESOS program
      - Personnel
      - Legislative activity
      - Public Partnership document
      - DOC-UCHC MOU
      - Data and Reports
    - UCHC Bonding Pre-UCONN 2000
      - Bond Commission
      - OPM correspondence
      - Photographs of decay
      - Legislative material
  - (Box 3)
    - Strategic Plan
    - Audit and Compliance
      - Health Center
      - Storrs
      - Board of Trustees
      - NCAA
      - Internal Audit/Financial Controls
    - Student Health
      - Reorg./UCPEA agreement
      - Billing
      - Grad Student (Storrs, Health Center, Law) Insurance coverage
    - Fringe Benefits--Storrs
      - Legislation
      - OPM/Treasurer/Comptroller
    - Administrative Cost Cap (Legis.)
    - Fees
    - DMHAS Research Program
    - Budget correspondence
    - Accounting/bursar
      - Write offs
      - Bursar holds
      - Inventory, Sec. 4-33a
  - (Box 4)
    - Information Technology
      - DO IT
      - HIPPA
      - CEN
      - CORE-CT
      - Pappas
    - UCEPI (including dissolution)
    - Technology Transfer
      - MOUs
      - Intellectual Property/Patent Counsel
      - Economic Development
      - Tech Park plans
    - CICATS
    - Stem Cell
  - (Box 5)
    - Tax issues--Storrs and Health Center
      - DRS correspondence
      - Food Sales
      - Ticket Sales
    - Human Resources
      - Collective Bargaining issues
        - AAUP (including adjunct, summer school)
        - UCPEA (including parking grievance)
        - NP2
        - Public Safety
    - Attorney General
      General note
      [See also Law School Library file, UConn 200 files, FOI file]
      - Correspondence
      - Requests for opinion
      - Outside counsel
      - Contract approval
      - Big East
    - Ethics Commission
    - FOI
    - Consumer protection
    - CHRO (includes set asides, Law School case)
    - OPM
    - DHE
      - ERIP/faculty reports (see also ERIP files)
      - Tuition study (plus CSU & CCs)
      - Reports (Brain drain, employer surveys)
      - Correspondence
  - (Box 6)
    - Master Plan (1995 on)
    - Co-Generation plant
      - Lease agreement
      - Correspondence
      - BOT activity
    - CT DPW
      - Babbidge Library
      - Natatorium
      - PAthobiology
      - Correspondence
    - HRH Atlas
      [See aso COO files]
      - LaRosa claim
      - Correspondence
  - Regional Campuses--includes some UCONN 2000 (Box 7)
    - Hartford Feasibility Study
      - RFP/Selection process
      - BOT
    - Stamford
      - Bartlett ARboretum
      - North Campus sale
      - Collaboration/plans
      - Correspondence
    - Tricampus
    - Torrington
    - Avery Point
      - Coast Guard
      - Lighthouse
      - Project Oceanology
      - Long Island Sound Council
      - Housing
  - (Box 8)
    - UConn Foundation
      - Audits
      - Tax issues
      - Internal audit
      - Legislative material
      - Matching grant program
      - Gift/Grant/Contract
      - Endowment/Disbursement policies
      - MOU
    - R & D Corp.
    - Law School Foundation
  - (Box 9)
    - Daily Campus
    - Athletics
      - Stadium
      - Capital
      - Football
      - General
    - Research
      - Animal Care
      - IT/Info Ed/HC
      - Research protocols
      - IDC re: other state agencies
      - GA/TA costs and charges
      - IDC protocols and issues
      - IMS
    - S. Rogers/Subway space
    - Water
    - Town of Mansfield